Today we're going to learn how to make coiling.
The coiling style is really interesting because you can make many different things out of it.
To start, you're going to want to use different kinds of wires.
Down here, we're going to start with a piece of industrial wire.
This is kind of a larger, thicker piece of wire that you're actually going to want to use professional wire cutters to cut.
Otherwise, if you use your pliers or your smaller wire cutters, you're going to probably damage them.
Using the industrial wire, you're going to cut off a piece of this and you're going to want very pliable wire.
This easily bendable and this is going to coil very nicely around the wire.
You can actually do this just with your hands or you can do with the pliers.
I'm going to start with my hands just wrapping the bendable wire around the very firm industrial wire.
With the industrial wire, you're going to want to keep in mind that unless you clean it with steel wool, there may be some residue that comes off of that.
That may be on your hands.
Wrapping that with your hands is very simple, or you can use your pliers to wrap it.
Holding it into to place and wrapping it around.
You'll end up with something like this.
This can be used as an accent to bracelets, jewelry and any type of earrings.
You can hang things off of it, or you can just keep that really cool style that makes it a great accent to any piece of jewelry.
That's how you coil around a larger wire.